<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on On Software and other things</title>
    <link>https://blog.aish.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on On Software and other things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 06:53:28 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.aish.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conway&#39;s Game of Life in WebAssembly</title>
      <link>https://blog.aish.io/post/conways-game-of-life-in-webassembly-and-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 06:53:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aish.io/post/conways-game-of-life-in-webassembly-and-rust/</guid>
      <description>Recently, after learning that the Rust compiler tool-chain, now supported WebAssembly as a target, I got interested in experimenting with WebAssembly. In order to explore how Rust could be used to write code that compiled to WebAssembly, I decided to implement Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life. My goal was to have as much of the grid traversing logic done in Rust as possible.
I started out by reading through a few chapters of the second edition of the Rust book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service discovery with mDNS, Raspberry Pi and Go</title>
      <link>https://blog.aish.io/post/service-discovery-with-mdns-raspberry-pi-and-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 20:54:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aish.io/post/service-discovery-with-mdns-raspberry-pi-and-go/</guid>
      <description>Today, yet again, I re-formatted by Raspberry Pi. It has become a sort of a ritual for me to format my Raspberry Pi and try out something new on it. This time around however, as I had moved to a new apartment, logging into my Raspberry Pi meant that I had to change my /etc/hosts mapping.
Now, /etc/hosts mapping had served my well but I had grown tired of updating this file, every time moved to a new place, despite of the static IPs that I assign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging</title>
      <link>https://blog.aish.io/post/debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 20:51:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aish.io/post/debugging/</guid>
      <description>The art of debugging is certainly an underrated art in the software industry today. As the startups of yesteryears turn into the bigger corporations of tomorrow the amount of debugging required to find and fix bugs in existing pieces of code will be more relevant in the years to come. With the ever changing landscape of software, perhaps the day is not far when corporations of tomorrow ask a candidate to debug an existing piece of code or to perhaps improve the efficiency of the same, as an interview exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Side Projects</title>
      <link>https://blog.aish.io/post/side-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 20:49:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aish.io/post/side-projects/</guid>
      <description>At times, people look at me with bizarre bewilderment when I say that I had a great time hacking a side project on a weekend. For someone not in the creative world, doing something that is done for their day job without getting paid seems like a crazy idea. Paul Graham, in his now famous essay, Hackers and Painters talks about how hackers, like painters and composers, are “makers”. Most “makers”, unlike administrators attain perfection by performing gradual refinement of their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you need a LinkedIn account ?</title>
      <link>https://blog.aish.io/post/do-you-need-a-linkedin-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 09:50:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aish.io/post/do-you-need-a-linkedin-account/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;rant&amp;gt;
After continuously questioning the value brought to me by my LinkedIn account, I finally deleted my LinkedIn account last week. The feeling of deleting my LinkedIn account was very liberating. Unlike other social network on the Internet that brought some value to me, my LinkedIn account was a constant source of recruitroll email. Sourcing agencies and recruitrolls from places which I&amp;rsquo;d not heard of sent a constant request to &amp;ldquo;add me as a connection&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery on Github</title>
      <link>https://blog.aish.io/post/github-starsystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 16:53:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aish.io/post/github-starsystem/</guid>
      <description>Github today has sort of a monopoly when it comes to developers open sourcing their work. Be it open sourcing side projects or storing your editor/shell configurations, Github is the go to place for most people. Now this is not a post about how important (and big!) Github has become, this post is about how hard it has become to discover great open source projects on Github.
Based on my experience, the usual discovery process starts out in IRC/Slack/Hacker News/Stack Overflow or during conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I dropped out of Stanford Ignite</title>
      <link>https://blog.aish.io/post/stanford-ignite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 09:46:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aish.io/post/stanford-ignite/</guid>
      <description>January 2015 was interesting month in many respects. First, I had just completed a two week long train journey covering all corners of India. Next, after spending about two years in the fintech world, I came to accept the fact that it was time for me to explore other domains.
In between all this, something unexpected happened. Sometime late the previous year, I had applied for the Stanford Graduate School of Business&amp;rsquo;s Stanford Ignite program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bon voyage</title>
      <link>https://blog.aish.io/post/bon-voyage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 16:57:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.aish.io/post/bon-voyage/</guid>
      <description>“Whatever grows will grow,
Whatever dies will die
Whatever works will work
Whatever flies will fly,
Whatever fails will fail
What’s meant to soar will soar,
I am planting seeds nothing more”
As the crowd started to sing along the chorus, the singer, a Wharton educated young man who gave up a career on Wall Street to find his purpose in serving others slowly waved back and sang along. Soon, the song got over and the audience of four hundred odd, 20 somethings applauded cherishing the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>